I did a keynote at Devox and I was
talking about how we will look more into
specifications less about code.
>> Never trust a monkey to write jet code.
Now the problem is that we decided we're
not going to review the tests. The
beauty of namely cucumber but generally
parsible spec [music] is that we don't
need a monthly
>> DevOps changes over the last 10 20 years
or so. We've seen platform teams. We've
seen this amazing DevOps engineer role
been created. I think it's definitely
not early to have like AI engineering
teams just because they're like among
us. Sometimes they present themselves as
Java LLMs which you shouldn't trust, but
AI engineering is something that should
probably exist.
>> We're talking a lot about spectrum
development here at Deox. So backlog
itself doesn't create specifications.
Backlog is a tool that AI agents use.
Hey, I want to build this feature. Use
backlog MD CLI to keep track of the
tasks and to split it into multiple
subtasks. But backlog itself should be
as minimal as possible.
>> We in the Java and Spring communities in
particular are in a uniquely amazing
position right now because most people
are going to use AI as an integration
with our existing business logic and
applications and services. That's all
written in spring. And so this is a
really natural place to start your AI
journey. I think.
[music]
>> Hey folks, Simon Maple here and welcome
to another episode of the AI Native Dev.
And today is a little bit of a special
episode because we're actually going
back and featuring some of the most
insightful pieces uh from uh previous
episodes including Baroo, Luran, Alex,
and Josh. Now, why did we pick these
specific speakers? Well, they're
actually also uh going to be in person
in New York with us next week uh at in
New York. And I say next week depending
on when you're listening to this. It is
the 18th and 19th of November in New
York City in in uh Brooklyn. And we have
a wonderful uh AI native dev conference
for you. Uh this is uh going to be
covering a whole bunch of different
topics, but really thinking about how we
use agents best and develop from a
specminded way uh going forward into the
into the future. So uh if you're
interested in that, check out a
native.iodevcon.
And a [snorts] little bit of a sneak uh
a little bit of a sneak preview here.
Uh, if you use the code Simon M50,
you can get 50% off your ticket. That's
Simon M50. And that brings the ticket
price down to $90. If you're local to
New York, please come and visit us. It's
going to be a good fun two days. One one
day packed with wonderful workshops and
the second day uh slammed with a whole
bunch of conference sessions as well as
of course that wonderful conference
track hallway track where we can chat
with like-minded folks about some of the
things that we're up to and make
wonderful networks and connections. So,
what are we going to hear about on
today's podcast? Well, we're going to
kick off um with uh Baroo and um Baruk
and I actually sat down um at a
conference called AI Focus back in
Stockholm in February this year and and
the the amount of similarities we had in
the way of thinking about how AI is
going to revolutionize and change the
way we develop software was was was
pretty amazing. And we we swapped some
fairly candid stories around uh you know
missing bugs, how we how how that review
process can let you down particularly in
a world where AI is generating more code
than ever and how to really make your AI
strategies absolutely bulletproof and
and and and really allow developers to
make sure they don't overlook the
possible challenges and and problems
that really matter in this new world of
AI development. So over to you Bru. You
said just before you said we want
something to automate the test, we want
something to create test because we
don't want to look at code, right? How
how true is that though, right? Because
I did a keynote at DevOps
>> um a couple of weeks ago, a few weeks
ago, and I was talking about how the
world is is moving into this new space
where developers will continue to be
creators.
>> We will we'll be we'll do things in a
different way. And one of those ways is
we will look more into specifications
less about code.
>> Exactly.
>> Devel a developer came up to me though
at the end.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> And and my last slide was cuz it was
Devox UK. It was keep calm.
>> Keep calm and carry on because we as
developers need need to need to change.
>> Evolve evolve.
>> He was he was super worried though. He
was like how can you put that slide up
when it means we're not looking at code.
He was he loves coding.
>> Yeah. Yeah, he absolutely his his safe
space was clearly in an IDE looking
through code. His mind was extremely
technical, loves the challenges, loves
the depth.
>> How do those people deal with that?
>> So, so I think when I say like we don't
want to look at code, we mostly don't
want to look at code which is not ours.
Like we're I mean we're humans well
selfish. We're are self-centered. We
most of the time listen to someone and
when we listen the the what we really do
is come up with a clever reply to what
they're about to say without even
listening. We know all those flows like
humans are flow
>> and and very self-centric. And this is
true about code as well. And the example
that I gave you earlier, I obviously
love in love with my code,
>> but I'm much less inclined to look at
your code review because well, okay,
that's just some other code.
>> Yeah. Or or my code that's one month
old,
>> which might as well be someone else's
code.
>> Absolutely. Right. So, so and and this
is and and this is the problem with the
generated code. It's someone else's
code.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So you might look at it and
especially now when it's a novelty, you
look at it out of curiosity to see what
LM does. Yeah. And you're like, "Oh my
god, this is brilliant. This is crap."
But but you you look at it because
you're curious like in in in 6 months
when more and more code will be
generated by you just okay, it's someone
else's code.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Right. So So first of all, you don't
want to look at this code
>> and obviously the non-technical people
definitely don't want to look at this
code.
>> They want to look at intent. They they
want to look at this test does this and
I can read that.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Right. And and and
generally the idea that code is that co
the tests are technical and written in
code I think and that's just an
assumption is one of the reasons why DDD
really didn't take over the world.
>> Mhm.
>> Because in the end of the day
>> TDD did you say that?
>> Yeah. testdriven development didn't take
over the world because in the end of the
day if developers are the only ones who
can write the tests and read the tests
>> the real question becomes at least for
me in my experience is why am I doing it
this way
>> I have a problem I'm biased for action
>> I know the solution in my I see
algorithms running code written in my
eyes I want to go and write code I want
to write tests
>> I don't mind write tests afterwards to
check that my code does what it's
supposed to do. But starting with code
doesn't make sense if developers are the
only one involved in the picture.
>> And I guess I'm not the only one who
thought about this problem. And this is
how one of the reasons why behavioral
driven development came to be 20 years
ago.
>> Yeah.
>> Like the BDD thing.
>> The way BDD works is like hey what if
the codes the the tests weren't defined
in code but were defined in spec. And
what BDD refers to spec is is some kind
of a um pseudo natural language it's
called girkin and it's basically set of
um rules that goes like given context
when something happened then expect
those results right so basically this is
the this is the steps and the beauty of
girkin spec is that is human readable
>> right and the idea was that it's also
human writable right so the the product
managers, the business people, maybe
even the customer can participate in
writing those specs.
>> And it's interesting because when agile
came in very often when we started
writing use cases and things like that
and starting with use cases, it was a
similar okay, the language is slightly
different, but it was actually kind of a
similar thing as a whoever I want to do
this with.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Right. And and then the
beauty of the idea of girkin spec was
that you take an algorithm and compile
those specs into tests. Mhm.
>> Now look at us moving one step forward
toward building the integrity that we
spoke about
>> because now suddenly
we can have something that technical
people and nontechnical people together
>> can sit and write.
>> Yeah.
>> And then if you remember the rest of the
chain that we started to build the spec
is compiled to the test.
>> Yes.
>> We can trust the test. That's exactly
what the spec was.
>> Yeah.
>> The code
>> implements the test.
>> Yeah.
>> So we can trust the code. Yeah.
>> Because it has to we have to because if
it passes the test, it does exactly what
the test want. And the tests are the
result of compilation of something that
we agreed our application should do.
>> So the areas that you care about, you
should have as many of those tests as
you can. the errors that you don't care
about, you just allow the LM to infer
whatever code it wants and whatever it
decides.
>> Yep,
>> that's the right way. That's that's a
way of doing it. That's an okay way.
>> If it's wrong, it means that you miss
some test that will enforce the way that
you want it and it means that it makes
some spec. It misses some spec. It
misses one of those use cases of given
when that you just need to go ahead and
>> it's an uncaptured intent essentially.
>> Yeah. Now the BDD also didn't really
take over the world. We it's even you
see it even less than than TDD actually.
>> And but again my speculation why is that
writing those structured
the structured intent the spec was still
a little bit too much for the
nontechnical people.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. Yes. Of course, it's readable,
but writing it, it's kind of annoying.
Those are, you know, when you look at
the when you speak with business people
or product managers, they are kind of
free souls. They want to create. They
want to write Shakespeare. They don't
want to write this rigid like structure.
>> You you read PDDs, it's like it's like
poetry.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so again, those specs didn't really
catch up because product managers like,
"Ah, that's too rigid." And then if they
don't do it, developers definitely not
going to do it,
>> right? Because for them reasons.
>> I also think I also think with the the
one of the issues with BDD is there was
no hard connection between the the the
BDD intense the spec part and anything
else. It was it was left up to someone
to then implement that. And as change
happened in the business and things like
that, it got stale. It gets stale in the
same way a PRD would. And then all of a
sudden, no one goes back to the PRD
because it's out of date. the code is
the is the source of truth.
>> But now if we automate all the way from
the spec to the end product, um the spec
is very important but no one wants to
write this girk and stupid thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Suddenly AI can help.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz we don't need to.
>> Right. Once we have a um like a
specification document.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. whatever you call software
definition document whatever there are
bunch of we can ask AI to formulate
those specs those when given when then
from it now we know that it will
hallucinate
>> Mhm.
>> and we know that the spec won't be
exactly as what we wanted it to do
>> for mainly two reasons. The first is I
mentioned the hallucinates. But the
second is that it's very hard for humans
to express um intent into words.
>> Yeah.
>> Because of context that we have in our
heads that obviously LLM lacks. So there
is this chasm between the prompt and the
intent between what we ask it to do and
what we really wanted it to do.
>> Yes.
>> So for those two reasons, the spec won't
be perfect. Mhm.
>> But coming back to the biggest benefit
of the spec because it is readable,
we can actually review it.
>> Yes,
>> it's different from tests that we
theoretically also could declare a
source of truth and review it instead of
specs. But as we spoke, we don't want to
read anyone else's code and especially
the nontechnical people that
>> they even cannot.
>> Yeah,
>> spec is different. Yeah. because it's
readable in your language. There are
hundred of languages translations of
Girkin spec. You can read it in Udo if
you feel like
>> and and this is suddenly something that
>> everybody um around the table
>> can sink on. Yeah. and say okay now we
can read the spec it's not painful it's
English and we can verify that what's in
the spec it's actually what we want it
to be generated from on pro
>> now if it's not we go back and forth we
iterate until it is or we just fix the
spec it's it's almost plain language
>> and and presumably you could almost like
use LLM as a judge as well to some
extent almost to as a as a as a final
backup to say look because because
people are going to be lazy right Yeah.
And I think this is one of those
interesting things where even if you
look at something like code review,
>> okay, people don't like looking at each
other's
code, but it's something that um the
more text, the more change there is,
we'll kind of like look at that and go,
"Yeah, that that kind of like looks
good. If there's two lines, we're going
to we're going to be questioning the
variable choices and things like that."
Right? So, if there is going to be a big
set of tests or a big specification, are
we actually going to go through it? an
LLM as a judge could actually be there
there are going to be levels of
automation that okay we need that backup
almost so there's potentially two levels
there one for the
>> and we can bring different models we can
generate spec with one model and then
ask another model if it thinks that the
intent is being captured
>> yes yeah
>> right and then it can we can iterate and
make this process and then but in the
end of the day human readable specs are
much easier to review than tests or
code. Yeah.
>> Right. And this is like the main idea.
>> So now we have the entire chain.
>> We start with the prompt like hey I want
to write an application that does ABC.
Come up with the set of specs that will
satisfy those requirements.
>> Then we have the specs.
>> We don't trust the LLM. So the problem
with LLM that
>> it is nondeterministic
not better than random code generator.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So my analogy
>> I like [laughter] that
>> my analogy is you remember this uh
thought experiments that if you give to
endless number of monkeys endless number
of typewriters eventually they will come
with uh the works of Shakespeare
>> this is an lens
>> they're are slightly better than random
monkeys typing on typewriters but
eventually that's exactly that they try
to get it right and it almost sometimes
almost works right So, and and and the
idea is that you cannot really trust a
monkey to write Shakespeare, especially
not on the first run. Yeah.
>> So, the the idea here is that
>> I think that's the that's the that's the
quote that we should take out from this
entire podcast. You can't trust a monkey
to write Shakespeare.
>> This is exactly
>> that's one thing I don't care whether
you're specentric, codeentric, that's
one thing we can all agree on.
>> Never trust a monkey to write
Shakespeare
>> or any kind of famous literature I'd
say.
>> Or or code.
>> Yeah. Or code. Well, some I've seen some
code.
>> No, but that's but [laughter] I've seen
some code, but was it cheap?
>> No, that's true. Absolutely not. Yeah.
>> So, let's make sure that we iterate
until it is. Yeah.
>> And that's exactly the idea, right? So,
the monkeys generate spec.
>> Will they do it right from the first
time? Probably not. We want to bring
other monkeys and and eventually the
most important is we look at the spec
and we say, "Well, it rhymes, but it's
not Shakespeare." Yeah.
>> Try it again with slightly different
prompt. Yeah. or we can just add the
spec directly.
>> Now once we have the spec we say okay we
cannot trust the monkey to generate
correct tests from the spec because we
cannot trust the monkey.
>> Yeah.
>> Now the problem is that we decided we're
not going to review the tests.
>> It's too much for us. It's someone
else's code. We don't want to do it.
>> The the beauty of namely cucumber but
but generally parsible spec
>> is that we don't need a monkey. Yeah,
>> because we take an algorithm and compile
the specs into tests deterministically
every time.
>> If you run it 10 times, you'll get the
same thing 10 times. Whereas if you do
it with LLMs, there'll be subtle
differences and maybe [laughter] and
since we don't review the test, we won't
even know that something is wrong. Yeah.
>> Right. So monkey is out of the picture
for this part.
>> Right. So we generate the tests. Now
once we have the tests we can let
monkeys lose
>> type on those typewriters forever until
the tests pass.
>> Yeah.
>> The only thing is we need to protect the
tests
>> because the monkeys will be inclined to
adjust the test to make them pass.
>> Yeah.
>> So how do you do it?
>> Whatever. Make the files read only. Put
them in a docker container and make them
unaccess like also read only.
>> Do whatever to protect the tests and
then let the monkeys loose. let them
type as long as they want to until the
test pass.
>> Yeah.
>> And now
we have the chain.
>> Right. We have a prompt that is
guaranteed to capture our intent
>> because we reviewed the specs.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we have the code that is
guaranteed to match the specs because we
generated code. We generate the test
without the monkeys and then the the
code actually passes the test. So we can
have the entire picture from our
ideiation to the end product that we can
absolutely 100% trust. This is an intent
integrity chain integrity
>> because we guarantee the integrity of
our intent.
>> Mhm.
>> In the code.
>> Thanks very much Baroo. And next up,
we're going to be chatting with uh Luran
Tal who I've known for many many years.
Um and Lauran, myself uh and Ashish uh
did a security round table not so long
ago. And in this we swap stories about
how AI tools while sometimes they can
help, they can actually sometimes make
things a little bit riskier as well. um
how security fails um and some things
are missing from uh AI tools that
provide us with data or results that
sometimes are a little bit misleading,
sometimes aren't deterministic um and
and understanding what's really beneath
the covers in your data and your
dependencies. So, if you care about
keeping your code safe, keep listening.
the LLM is just as capable of of, you
know, suggesting fixes first first time
around versus identifying issues and
then creating fixes around them. Um,
what are the risks in relying upon those
fixes to or suggested fixes to to my
code? And I guess we're talking about
security here today, but we just had a
performance session uh last last time
around. Um, it's it's going to it's
going to apply to a ton of different
areas, but specifically and Luran, I
think you're probably well placed here
from the first party code point of view.
Yes, AI can suggest fixes. What are the
risks?
>> So, I would say it's can suggest fixes,
but the fixes will be suggested based on
some, you know, statistical model out of
whatever it got trained on and whatever
context it thinks it has, but it doesn't
really has the right context and I think
that is key. So like there's so much
that is going on within like you know
when you go beyond like the benchmark
you know sample repository that you
compare you know various tools around
and code and like the to-do apps that
you build with with AI once you go deep
down enough and things get complicated.
I think at that point there's a ton of
context that is needed and understanding
of code flow. So I will give you one
example that I think makes total sense
where LLMs would actually try to fix
something but would actually get you get
you hacked. So imagine that you are on a
piece of code in a in your file and you
are working with URLs and you are you
know you you you practice something
that's maybe like you know URL encoding
or like you like ask the like the result
of the AI is giving you some code that
relates to that and you ask it to like
secure it right and it says okay let's
do URL encoding or the other way around
let's do URL decoding whatever like the
depends on like the current process
let's say [clears throat] let's say that
this is what it suggests and by the way
that's that's probably one of the things
it should do so like that's a proper
process but what happens when it is not
aware that somewhere up the chain right
so I mean in some you know let's say
this is your you know service and in
some other service you interact with or
you know the route the controller
whatever you know the the architecture
is you actually already did a URL
encoding so now you have double URL
encoding and that is potentially like a
security vulnerability like waiting to
happen due to the double encoding And so
if the LLM doesn't know to like trace
your code paths and say well well you
actually did an encoding before you
should not really reapply the encoding
because you could suffer at the double
encoding injection then that's going to
get you busted. And so that's why it
needs more than being just a statistical
model and sometimes like vulnerabilities
in most of the cases honestly are very
nuanced and very complicated. While it's
sometimes easy to just you know
demonstrate some code injection, some
cross-ite scripting that we show in a
vulnerability and you know there it is.
It's it's usually most of the time
vulnerabilities are chained together.
They are more complicated. People you
know chain one to another like a
prototype pollution to do code injection
to do command injection to open a shell.
There's like a a layered approach when
things happen in the real world rather
than what we kind of you know demo. So
having that nuance and understanding
is is I don't think that kind like fits
the statistical model and maybe those
things maybe those LLMs and AI agents
and the whole you know genai you know
general way of coding gets smarter where
it will be able to then kind of like
infuse several learnings and several
paradigms together like both the model
but also some applied you know uh logic
and something else that would be great
but like at this point in time it's just
super basic and it's as It kind of saved
you the time to like Google how to
properly do, you know, path validation
versus just asking the LLM. It's not at
that point where you would ask it to fix
it and you could count on it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Very interesting. We
got a minute or so till Q&A. Um let's
let's invite the audience to also ask
some questions. Um while the audience is
thinking of questions and pinging them
into the chat, I'd be interested in just
asking more of a cultural question. And
I think when we think about uh you know
DevOps changes over over the last 10 20
years or so, we've seen platform teams,
we've seen this this amazing DevOps
engineer role been created. Um I I
personally see there's a place on that
platform team for maybe certain security
engineers and and people who do work
closely with with the developers the
paved road style approach when we so
first of all may maybe it'd be
interesting to hear your thought on that
but beyond that do do we see from an
organizational change point of view an
AI security paved road or anything like
that also sitting in the in the um in in
the platform team? I'd I'd love to know
how you think the the teams are going to
change. Ashish, why don't you lead us
with this?
>> Uh I think the the so there is already I
guess many companies have already
started working on AI projects and the
way they're dealing with this at this
point in time is the platform engineers
themselves are the ones who are because
from a workload perspective if you look
at the components that get
>> used for building an AI application
those really haven't changed. I guess
you still use Kubernetes as your
foundation layer. you still have
databases. So all that layer hasn't
really changed. So those people would
still continue to work on it. I think
the only the only point you would see
evolution like that when the number of
AI applications outweigh the number of
regular applications you have. So it
kind of happened to your point example
where
>> we started with DevOps. We had cloud
became cloud security engineers, cloud
security this, cloud security that then
kubernetes became popular then oh I just
do kubernetes security engineer. I think
it just comes down to if we ever get to
a point where the number of applications
which are AIdriven in your organization
are more than the regular non-AIdriven
or by then they are quote unquote legacy
application then yeah maybe uh we'll see
that but maybe not right now I guess
kind of where I'm coming from.
>> Yeah. Any thoughts, Lean?
>> Yeah, I I agree. I think it's a bit
early to call like an AI security
engineer. I think it's definitely not
early to have like AI engineering teams
just because that's like very
like that's like like AI AI is here,
right? Like LLMs are here. They're like,
you know, among us. Um sometimes they
they present themselves as Java LLMs,
which you shouldn't trust. Uh but, you
know, they are among us. And I think AI
engineering is like is is something that
that should probably exist. I think AI
security engineering is is a bit deep
down. It's it's indeed like I don't know
if there's like Kubernetes security
engineers. It's like very very very
specific. You kind of like I think like
depend on the tooling the ecosystem you
know the foundation um to like run a
bunch of like you know the security
responsibility to an extent you kind
like outsource the risk because it's a
third party and things like that. Um and
I I I somewhat feel like a shish that
it's kind of early to understand what it
is since we don't exactly know like even
how to secure it properly. So um it's
we'll see.
>> Yeah. Question coming in from the
audience. Uh Min asks it's interesting
that open source code used to be seen as
more secure than proprietary code
because open source projects are
transparent about potential
vulnerabilities. Um I gather from what
you are saying now is that no is that no
longer the case when it comes to models
and agents. Did I understand this
correctly? I think it's still the case
though. I think it's still the case that
both open source and proprietary data
cannot be trusted. That's where the I
mean I guess the whole foundation or the
nervousness which we all have is that no
matter which way you face if you look at
internally uh there was the Ashish
example that I went for who left left a
bag of rotten tomatoes uh ages ago that
is still hanging around there are parts
of the organization that we still don't
touch or talk about that is it so that
is never going away it's still going to
be there if you look at open source uh I
think I'll go back to the episode
example that you gave Simon earlier uh
where Arman kind of spoke talk about the
levels of like I did my first GitHub
repository back when I was trying to
understand what what is it like what is
it code something and my that my that
repository is still there to the point
that today when I'm teaching people
Kubernetes and cloud and all of that I
have the mature repository as well I
mean the same Ashish has two
repositories which are completely
different experiences I've never touched
the the first one again because I'm just
too embarrassed to talk about it now
that I did it publicly but Still uh I
think that's where I find that I would
say there's untrust or nervousness on
both sides. I I wouldn't say one is
better than the other.
>> Yeah.
>> Or more secure.
>> I would take I think it's more nuanced
and it's it's really hard to compare
open source code like like comparing
third party vulner uh third party
dependencies with like uh third party
models if if you if that's what you kind
of want to compare. It's super hard
because the I think the foundation is
very different. So for example to to
review and scan like get an audit of an
open source third party package I could
I could see the maintainers I could see
who contributed I could see a git log of
all the code added how it was added when
fixes were made right like in the code
in the releases I can see what third
party it use uses to do things um I can
have like you know provenence and at the
station at like the signature level of
how how uh versions were published. I
don't really have that level of data at
the model, right? Like I can't see ex I
cannot see like how exactly was it
trained. Uh I I I am being told how but
I don't know how it was actually. I
don't think like the same uh the same
standards of how you do code to how you
train models exist yet. And I think
that's like the the nuance that kind of
kind of escapes and it's it's kind like
easy to maybe overlook, but I think
that's that's an important aspect when
you need to audit, you know, code versus
versus a model.
>> Yeah, we're pretty much out of time, but
I want to add this last question because
I feel like it's a really great question
from Macy here. What about social
engineering risks? uh when teams
leveraging um generative AI, what steps
can be taken um what steps can teams
take against this or is it too early? Do
we not know what those are just yet?
>> I would say there's definitely some and
I guess there are different ways to take
the social engineering aspect. The one
that comes to mind with Gen AI is the
fact that I work as a developer and I
want to know what's the salary of
Ashisha Cisa because I'm just curious he
seems to be quite fancy on the internet.
I wonder where he gets all the money
from. So, so I the the way people are
talking about this at the moment is that
there needs to be almost like a quote
unquote data access manager for a lack
of a better word. Uh the the way people
are doing this is how do you manage
access for different identities based on
their roles. That is one aspect for
social engineering. Uh I I would argue
this could be done better in the AI
world because you have a lot more sense.
you have a lot more understanding of
where your data is, what kind of data it
is and who can access it and what they
should be doing. It's not just a policy
document, it's actually implemented. I
think that's where I feel that'll be
really interesting, but in some aspects
really early because we haven't really
seen AI based attacks at scale. So, we
don't really know what social
engineering could be like as well. So,
maybe in that aspect maybe too early.
>> Cool. I'm being shoved off shave shoved
off stage here because we have another
session starting in just a few minutes.
Um so first of all a massive thank you
to both Ashish and Lauran. It's an
absolute pleasure to have you on the
native dev.
>> Likewise. Thank you for having us.
>> Thanks very much Lauran and Ashish. Next
up we go back to another conference
actually this time Devox Belgium where I
interviewed uh Alex and Alex uh who's
one of the authors or the main author of
uh Backlog MD. uh he unpacks why this
kind of like coding by gut feel can
absolutely lead to chaos. And in this
session we talk a lot about how uh
specification tricks really allow us to
define what needs to be not what what
needs to be built and and really manage
this in backlog MD to be able to build
uh using uh our ticketing system as well
as coding agents uh and really get
projects uh back under control fast. Uh
over to you Alex.
>> So yeah, we're talking a lot about
spectriven development uh here at DevOps
and and Alex um first of all tell us a
little bit about yourself because I
think some of the things that we're
going to talk about with with backlog
and things like that is very much is
very much kind of in you know built in a
in a in a spec driven mindset uh in
terms of in terms of going forward. So
tell us a little bit about yourself a
little bit about Batlog MV.
>> Right. So I'm a lead engineer in Vienna
for a gaming company
>> and I'm coming from an agile environment
using scrum uh having all the
requirements with PS uh thinking ahead
few months uh ahead with all of the
features like really thinking them
through and then there's the coding part
and right now everything happens like
between humans so it's uh uh no AI no
nothing just classic development ment we
have a back end team, we have a a mobile
uh development team. So they all
collaborate together.
uh this is uh what I'm doing during the
day but obviously in my free time I'm
trying to learn as much as possible
about AI and trying to keep up to date
with the latest trends and uh backlog MD
was um basically my my trial of AI and
like a challenge for myself to really
try to be as autonomous as possible and
try to uh let AI code 100% of the time
in my tasks. M
>> so
um what was the reason why I started
building backlog MD is uh I started with
side projects I started working with AI
I was just prompting prompting all the
time and I was just getting really bad
results I was basically doing vibe
coding and then I realized how what
successful uh processes I use at work
that make makes the collaboration
between humans uh effective enough to to
uh build successful gaming features and
then I try to learn from the human
process and try to adapt it to AI and by
doing this I realized the most important
part are the specs. So everything starts
with specifications, requirements, not
just about the feature you want to
build, but also everything around it
like security specifications,
um, CI/CD specifications like just the
language that you should use like C#,
TypeScript, Java, whatever language and
you should have all of this context
uh, right before you start. So in order
to be really successful with your tasks.
>> Really, really interesting. Let's just
break that down a little bit. So, so you
you were doing a lot of vibe coding.
What typical tools were you using for
vibe coding?
>> Um, cloud MD um um cloud.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so and and what were the what were
the ex what are the examples of that
those problems did you did you kind of
hit in code? So the problems were
uh like a single single task problems
that would uh repeat themselves on every
single task. So what I want to mean by
this is uh I tell the agent to build a
certain feature and he reached the goal
and he managed to build this feature but
by uh going back and forth on on a lot
of things and with the next tasks I
would repeat again the same same
instructions and I would stumble upon
the same issues again and again and
again. This is the problem with vibe
coding. basically every time you have a
new session with your agent and you try
to build as much as possible within your
context window.
>> Mhm.
>> And this doesn't scale obviously.
>> Yeah. And as soon as you close that
window, context is lost, you have to
build that up again in your next window.
>> Exactly. And maybe you forgot the
instructions that you told him to
prevent certain issues and you have
again the same
>> problems. And a lot of the things that
you mentioned that you would put into
specs like security considerations and
things like that. How would you describe
those needs to your vibe coding tool?
>> Yeah, so obviously with vibe coding you
um can like do a lot of damage. You can
deploy some some changes, some patches
to production that actually break
things. Um and you need guardrails but
you need these guardrails also with
humans like the we we all use
specifications about uh security and
measures that check check uh points for
example like staging environment to test
all of these measures to to prevent
issues and with VIP coding suddenly
everyone forgot about them.
>> Yeah. So what did then you kind of like
mentioned you you moved more into the
spec environment. Tell us a little bit
about that. Yes. So I started creating
markdown tasks manually. Actually before
that I started creating a huge markdown
with all of the specifications and all
of the features that I wanted to build.
Uh the problem with that it was a a huge
context and I would uh immediately
inject this context uh into the model
and uh the agent with this model will
maybe be effective maybe not and I will
not have uh good success rate and
sometimes I will have to roll back but
it would be very hard to roll back a
whole product or a whole feature and
what's interesting there is you're
nowhere near the context window you
nowhere near the the the maximum context
size.
>> Yeah. you're just hitting that mark
whereby the results based on the amount
of context you provide degrades
massively significantly from from that.
>> Yes. The the this agent have um feature
called compaction.
>> Uh this basically tells the agent to
make a summary of all of the previous
conversation and start with the minimum
context from that summary. But the
problem is that the instructions that
are contained in this summary are half
of the ones that you instructed him
initially and um you have to um most
likely start from scratch again because
you don't know what he he misses.
>> Mhm. Okay. Okay. So what was what's
what's next in the in the spectrum?
>> So what what was next? The immediate
next step was to split the big markdown
file into smaller tasks. So I would have
similar to how you have in uh Jira or in
Lina or other project management tools
single tasks that uh just define what
has to be built. And I basically
translated this into markdown files
because markdown is a universal language
that is plain text with formatting uh
that both humans and agents can uh
understand very well and agents were
actually more effective and I could
easily roll back single tasks at the
time. Mhm. Mhm.
>> And you did this manually or you did
this with
>> Yes. at the very beginning I was
creating manually and I uh when I reach
around 50 manual created tasks I I was
uh like any power software engineer I
would try to automate this. How can I
automate this manual creation of tasks?
So I build backlog MD for uh enabling
this and have an easy way to create task
by uh using your terminal.
>> The best way to learn about it is to see
it right. Should we uh should we take a
look at uh a quick demo of backlog?
>> Uh sure.
>> Talk us talk us through it.
>> So the first thing that you would do
with uh to even run backlog you would
have to install it.
>> So you can use ban, you can use mpm or
brew uh and you should install it
globally uh in your computer. Why
globally? Because then you don't have to
install it in every single project that
you're using and you can immediately use
it in every folder. So this is going to
take few seconds and
>> even on conference Wi-Fi just
>> yes exactly
>> uh this is because ban is very fast on
installing dependencies.
>> Mhm.
>> And afterwards uh you can run backlog as
as this no other instructions. This is
going to give you some uh some initial
hints what you can do with backlog. So
you can see here you can create tasks,
you can list the tasks, you can see the
board. I will uh show it very quickly.
You can also run a browser and again I
will go in detail about this and an
overview that shows what the statistics
about your project. How many tasks are
finished and how many are remaining and
the link to the docs. And the next thing
to to do normally you would want to
create tasks but because this is I'm
running backlog inside the backlog
project and I'm using backlog to keep
track of the tasks for backlog itself I
already have hundreds of tasks. So let
me show you how it looks the board.
So backlog uh gives you a canon board
>> that is configurable with how many
statuses you want. So the default ones
are to do in progress and done. And here
you can see what is going on in this
project. And all the tasks that you see
here are in sync between multiple git
branches. So backlog uses natively git
>> to fetch information from other
branches. So if you work with other
people uh as long as they push uh the
changes on a task. So for example, I
take over task 200 [music] and I assign
it to myself and I put it in progress.
as I make a push on my feature branch,
you will see it also in your backlog
instance on on the main branch for
example. So this is also nice to to use
it as a collaboration tool.
>> And can you filter based on branches and
things like that here?
>> Uh so uh the the logic behind it is it's
a bit hidden from from the developers. Y
>> uh backlog should be smart enough to
find what is the task with the latest
updated date.
>> Nice. And that means is the the mo the
newest state. Obviously if you change a
task um by mistake this will trigger uh
that that task is the has the latest
update version. But in normal use cases
this should not happen.
>> Gotcha. Okay. And what you can do from
here you can find the details of the
task. So for example uh let's see one uh
task that I would like to build next. Um
this one. I press enter and I
immediately see the details of the task.
So what I would like to have in the near
future is drag and drop in the
terminals.
>> Yeah.
>> So like you do in J you drag your task
from uh to-do to in progress. I would
like to achieve the same in in the this
canon board. So this is the task for
that feature is not implemented yet.
It's in to-do. And what we can see here
are the task ID, the title, some
metadata about the task, some
dependencies because backlog also
supports dependencies that basically um
prevents the the agent to work on tasks
which are not ready to be started. So
this is also important um in a specd
driven development. We have a
description that basically tell us why
are we even doing this feature. So
adding the drag and drop functionality
uh uh using shift plus arrow uh will
allow the users to to [music]
not leave this terminal interface and to
change the progress very easily. So this
is very nice from a user perspective.
And we have some acceptance criteria
which are the core of backlog. Basically
the acceptance criteria is something
that can be testable, something that can
be easily verified and measurable and uh
basically represents the increments of
imple like the smaller increments within
this single task.
>> Mhm.
>> And whenever an acceptance criteria is
done, it will be ticked. So I will show
you very soon how that looks.
>> Uh let's open a task that has been
completed. Um
this one for example. So you can see the
status is done.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh it has been uh taken over by open eye
codeex. Uh also another feature uh uh
about backlog is labels. So you can
label your your tasks and filter um
later uh by labels.
And here we can see the acceptance
criterias are all obviously implemented.
We have here an implementation plan. Uh
I will talk about uh the implementation
plan a bit later but it's part of the
spec development. You always want to uh
ask the agent how he would like to
develop this task and then you review
and then at the end we have the
implementation nodes which are sort of
um permanent context what has been done
in this task. So if for any reason a
human or an agent would like to see what
happened in this task, they would read
implementation notes and have this
permanent context about it.
>> So yeah, this is uh the primary
interface. We also have a task list view
uh which is this one. Here we have just
a
a long backlog of tasks. Uh we can also
um check the details and if it's longer
scroll.
We can also search for tasks. So maybe
let's
find tasks about tailwind. Uh
yeah, this this one uh there is no task
actually about tailwind but anyways
>> um you we can also filter by status. So
to-do done in progress uh priority
again. So, this is also like a second
command panel where you manage your
tasks.
>> Yep.
>> Um, and that's basically it for the UI.
Um, we also have a web interface.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh, for people that like to have more uh
um visual
uh guey for for interacting with task.
We also have a plane mode for AI agents.
Let me show you that one because I think
it's more important. So for example uh
we were looking at task 200. So backlog
task 200 minus minus plane.
This will show the same information but
in plain text. And this is what agents
should use.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I see.
>> Yeah. Okay. And and so let's talk a
little bit about I want to kind of talk
a little bit about the way in which so
you mentioned you built this a lot
through specifications and things like
that. How did you go about building
those specifications? Did you use a
tool? Did you handcraft the
specifications yourself? How did you how
did you deliver that to them?
>> So it that's quite interesting because
the first tasks I created manually. So
this kind of format I came up manually
by creating them myself.
>> Mhm.
>> And after four or five tasks [music]
I already had backlog CLI command to
create tasks. So afterwards I just
recursively started using backlog to
manage tasks about backlog.
>> And so backlog creates the specification
about the task which is essentially the
thing or not necessarily specification
of the task but the information in that
task that it can be used as a spec for
an agent to
>> is it to implement that change would you
say?
>> Uh so yes and no. So backlog itself
doesn't create specifications. So
backlog is a tool that AI agents use
>> but it's not calling agents. which is
not connected to AI agents by by
default. So you would have to start the
flow this way. So I start code or codex
or jamina CLI and I tell this agents hey
I want to build this feature use backlog
and this CLI to keep track of the tasks
and to split it into multiple subtasks.
>> There are some agents uh instructions
that come with backlog that tells the
agent how to use backlog itself. So
afterwards the agents will know how to
split a bigger task that you have in
mind into smaller tasks that fit
backlog.
>> But backlog itself uh it should be as
minimal as possible and should not be in
the way. It should be sort of a tool
that both the human and the agent use on
the side.
>> Gotcha. Gotcha. So so it's claw that
kind of like determines the split almost
and then adds that into into
>> bat world. Thanks very much Alex. And to
wrap up this episode, we finally have
the wonderful Josh Long, amazing spring
advocate. And I actually met up with
Josh at Deox UK. And now I'm starting to
feel bad that three of these four are at
conferences. Uh but it kind of, you
know, it's it's nice that this is all
wrapping up next week as well uh at the
AI Native Dev Conference. So to to wrap
things up, uh Josh and I talk about the
ups and down ups and downs of bringing
AI into live business code and we talk
about some real production war stories,
um some tips about how you you steer
clear of of the typical roadblocks. Um
there's a ton of great information here
and and live coding uh that really um
helps people get AI into action and and
and started in their Java environments.
Um, and just of course before I before I
wrap up here, I want to just let you
know, remind you next week on the 18th
and 19th, we are in New York with the AI
Native Devcon. Uh, feel free to join us.
We have a bunch of workshops and a bunch
of sessions. And of course, if you use
Simon M50,
Simon M50 as a code, you can get 50% off
your ticket price. Hope to see you
there. And over to Josh. We're at Devox
UK today and joining me is the wonderful
Josh Long.
>> Hi buddy.
>> Josh, how are you doing?
>> Oh, so good. I'm I'm at Devox UK.
DevOKUK as we call. [laughter]
>> Um Josh, we go back like how long? Many
years. 15 years.
>> Too long.
>> 2010 maybe.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think so. And and and I
I've been a fan since 2011. [laughter]
>> Was 2010 a bad year?
>> No, I'm just kidding. No. Uh that you I
mean you you created a you you you
brought so much joy to my heart, but
then you brought joy to the world. I
remember the the virtual jug. Yes. That
was I just think about that all the
time. That was such a genius idea. A
decade ahead of its time. It took a
pandemic for the rest of the world to
realize. Oh yeah. Genius. You know,
>> and that's still going now. There's
almost 20,000 people in the virtual jug
these days. Wow.
>> Apparently. Apparently.
>> It's crazy. So, um, people know Josh
Long as the Spring advocate, the
advocate [clears throat] in the Java
space, but, um, how long have you been
with, uh, with with, uh, Spring,
Pivotal, VMware, Broadcom?
>> I don't 2010.
2010.
>> Uh, and, uh, you know, still going
strong. Yeah. But, uh,
>> yeah, it's about about as long as I've
known you, actually. Yeah. It's been
coincident. Wonderful.
>> Yeah. Awesome. And today we're going to
be talking about um Spring AI.
>> We'll be talking a little bit about uh
perhaps why people will use AI when
they're typically a Java developer,
Spring developer. So we'll talk a little
bit uh about the reasoning behind why
people use it and then we'll go into
some demo as well to talk about to
actually show Spring AI in action. But I
guess first of all, what's the
capabilities of Spring AI? What does it
what does it provide? So, Spring AI is
is your one-stop shop for AI
engineering. And uh I think we in the
Java and Spring communities in
particular are in a uniquely amazing
position right now. Just an amazing
position because we're uh most people
are going to use AI as an integration
with their existing business logic and
applications and and services. That's
all written in Spring. That's all
written on the JVM and Cotlin and Java
and whatever, right? That that you're
already there. They just want to hang AI
off integrations off of that code and
make it work. your business logic, the
things that drive your business and the
data that that that feeds your business,
that's all governed and controlled by
and orchestrated by Springbased
microservices. And so this is a really
natural place uh to start your AI
journey, I think, is to enable access to
that data and to that business logic
from your AI models and via your AI AI
models. So uh sure, some people are
going to use Python to train new models,
>> but that's not most of us. Most of us,
in the same way that most of us aren't
building our own SQL database, you know,
and C or whatever, uh, most of us don't
need to do that either.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I I think we're in a uniquely great
position. And when it comes to
production, production worthy, scalable,
fast, secure, uh, observable production,
that's, you know, the JVM is there's
nothing like it. Nothing like that, you
know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So, AI, how does AI
fit into all of this? Uh,
>> well, we have this point of view,
>> right? We've got so you know spring uh
uh is a set of frameworks spring
framework and then spring boot on top of
that and a bunch of verticals on top of
that serving different use cases
including microservices batch processing
integration data uh security whatever
right and we have one called spring AI
which goes GA by the way 1.0 OG 20th of
March. No, May. So, we we had ambitions.
I think I think uh I don't know if I'm
speaking out of school here or not. I
think at one point we hoped it would go
GA. Uh but um and you're not going to
believe this. The AI space has changed.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> I don't believe it.
>> No, I you you
>> if there's one if there's one constant,
>> right,
>> it's a it's the AI space.
>> AI's change is too much. Yeah.
>> Um it's too quick, too fast, too much,
too. Whatever. We have a whole team of
people working on this
>> and even they uh and we got you know
it's one of our most busy
>> uh open source projects right it's
>> the star history is like a
>> hockey hockey puck you know just hockey
uh stick rather just just through the
roof meteoric rise in in popularity and
GitHub issues
>> and and contributions and everything
just it's yeah so every time we think
we're about to settle down and reach a
GA mouse or GA release whole new
paradigm gets dropped in our laps
>> I just I just assumed it was GA just by
the amount I hear about it.
>> It's mature. People are using it. It's
growing all the time. It's it's very
very popular. But obviously, we've just
wanted to get to a point where we had
>> the things that mattered. And um I think
we're there.
>> So as soon as there's a week of no
change or May 20th,
>> whichever should happen,
>> whichever should happen first.
>> Yeah. Well, I think it's going to be May
20th either way. At that point, we're
we're on the 7th of May. So
>> yeah,
>> got a couple weeks. Yeah.
>> We don't even have two weeks of that.
>> You know,
>> in fact, depending on when this gets
released.
>> Yeah. We could be around May 20th. It
may be May 27th, actually.
>> Actually, that might that may be seven
days too late. Yeah.
>> Really? So, let's just say let's just
say Spring AI is out today.
>> Yeah, it's out. Yeah.
>> Go get the bits. Fresh off the we might
even have the first catch at least. Who
knows? Yeah. By the time you watch this,
but all that to say, things are moving
quickly. And uh that's okay. That's
okay. But remember, we want to pair uh
the innovation in the AI space with the
idiomatic uh sort of approach to
building apps that Spring has always so
embodied and um we want that to to build
upon some of the pillars that Spring has
always talked about, right? Portable
service abstractions to isolate you from
the uh differences between different
models and image models, chat models, uh
transcription models, etc. Um uh
dependency injection, aspect oriented
programming and spring boot style auto
configuration, you know. Yeah. So you
take those four pillars and um did I say
three earlier? I was talking about four.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh you get an approach that it gives
you purchase in this new strange land,
right? It gives you uh uh the ability to
get hit the ground running. You already
know all that stuff. You already know
the component model.
>> It's just a matter of applying that
those those facets of your understanding
of Spring to this new domain.
>> And you're going to demo Spring AI.
>> I sure am. We'll talk a little bit about
as we go through. We're going to build a
very simple application here because
we're kind of pressed on time. Uh, but I
wanted to demonstrate a simple
application that helps. We're going to
build an assistant to help people adopt
dogs, right? And I talk about dogs all
the time because I think it's really
cute. And I've got I've got a dog and I
I talk about uh this in particular, I
talk about my dog who's
>> Look, he's not the best dog, but he's
mine. And we'll, you know, we'll
>> he's a good dog. He's still a good dog.
>> He's he's
[laughter]
>> Look at that dog. That's a That's a cute
dog right there. So, uh, all that to
say, um, not good, but he's ours. And
his name is Peanut. Okay. And Peanut is
the worst dog. Except then I met this
other dog in the I learned about this
other dog in the pandemic whose name is
Prancer. Prancer. Turns out even more of
a spicy uh dog, right? And this owner,
this lady was trying to find a new home
for this dog. And she put out this
hysterical ad saying, "Okay, I've tried
I've tried for the last several months
to post this dog for adoption and make
him sound palatable. The problem is he's
just not. There's not a very big market
for neurotic, man-hating, animal-hating,
children hating dogs that look like
gremlins. And she continues, "Kuna
Chihuahua, you probably know what I'm
talking about. He's literally the
Chihuahua meme that describes him as
being 50% hate and 50% tremble." She
continues, "I kind of liked him better
that way. He was quiet and just laid on
the couch. Didn't bother anyone. I was
excited to see him come out of his shell
and become a real dog. I'm convinced at
this point that he's not a real dog, but
more like a vessel for a traumatized
Victorian child that now haunts our
home." And she continues and this goes
on for a long time and she signs off.
Oh, he's only 2 years old and will
probably live to be 21 through pure
spite. So take that into account if
you're interested. That said, super
cute, right? Like that's a cute dog. I
>> That is a cute dog. I'd pet that dog.
Oh, look at him.
>> I've got two Labradors. I got two
Labradors. I don't have that.
>> The big dogs are great. The big but my
dog, just like this dog, small. They
have the Napoleon complex, you know,
like the something about it.
>> Yeah. Angry. Angry by default.
>> By default. And I don't know why cuz I
just want to I just want to pet this
cute little guy. Um, so, so I think
about this talk a lot too. Rentree all
the time, right? I mean, just just how
did such a dog exist? And by the way,
this ad went viral, right? This ad went
viral. So, for example, here's a People
magazine talking about Prancer, the
demonic Chihuahua. Here's um USA Today
talking about Prancer, the demonic
Chihuahua. Here's BuzzFeed
um
talking about the nightmare Chihuahua,
the viral nightmare Chihuahua. And of
course, here's the New York Times
talking about Prancer, the demonic
Chihuahua, right? So, very, very famous
dog. And I thought, well, that's that's
nice. That's good that people learned
about this dog.
>> But that's not how most people roll,
right? Most people don't find dogs by
finding them on the uh on the internet,
right? Like you go to a shelter and you
have a conversation with somebody and
you you interview to to discover the dog
of your dreams or in this case uh
nightmares. So, what I wanted to do is
to build such an assistant to help
people go through that process, right?
To to find the right dog. So we're going
to go to the start.springo. Uh I've
already got this dog database here and
you can see there's our doggo prancer.
His ID is 45 and his name is Prancer,
right? He's in a postgris database. So
we're going to build an application
here. We're going to call it assistant.
>> Postgress database strong enough to
contain prancer today.
>> Yeah, it's it is a very very tough ask.
[laughter] Yeah. Uh gravm. We use the
web stuff. We use um open AI. Now I'm
going to use open AI. It's just a very
good model and a lot of people probably
have access to it, but it's not the only
model. Well, not even close. Here in uh
data data privacycentric sensitive
Europe, you might prefer something a
like a llama which is a fine choice or
uh you know alternatively we got things
like bedrock and uh Gemini and um
>> everything everything I mean just
there's dozens and dozens of different
models that we officially support and
the ones that we don't officially
support most of them speak the uh Open
AI API
>> and so you can talk to them via our open
AAI integration. Right. So I'm going to
bring in OpenAI. I've got the web
support, don't I? Oh, I took that away.
I'll bring in the spring boot actuator
support. Um, and I'm going to bring in I
need a vector store. Now you can use
look just type vector store. And you can
see you got mil, you got neo forj, pine
cone, mariab, weate, Oracle, reddus, uh,
cudrant, azour, apache, cassandra,
chroma, elastic search, MongoDB, PG
vector, typense, Azour, Cosmos DB, etc.
I'm going to use PG vector store because
I've got a SQL database in Postgres.
This is a a plugin, right? vector
plugin. So, we're gonna go ahead and
open that up.
>> So, what you did there was you added a
bunch of down a bunch of dependencies
into your Spring project, which then
allows you to effectively build that
into I presume a Maven pom file. Yep.
When you build that, it will pull all
the Java dependencies straight into your
uh into your Spring project.
>> You know it. And actually, you know what
I did? You know what I did wrong there?
I uh I forgot to select
uh PG. No, I forgot to select dev tools.
Okay.
>> So, I'm gonna actually go down to M7
here because I don't know what the they
changed something in M8 and I don't
remember the idiomatic way to do it
already, but I'll use that. It's
downloading the internet which is not a
good thing. It's we're actually on
conference Wi-Fi. No, we're not. Stop
that. Stop it. No, [laughter] the the go
I'm used I'm I'm live streaming here.
Okay. So, Intelligj is amazing. But if
you start the project in Intelligj
before uh adding the um dev tools,
>> yeah,
>> it'll it'll not use it won't enable the
dev tools integration.
>> Gotcha.
>> So I I retroactively added the dev tools
uh there, didn't I?
I did not. Oh, that is so awkward. Okay,
we'll go back over here.
Copy and paste.
Dev Tools is there now, right?
>> There you go.
>> So, now we'll go back again, do this
whole thing again. Normally, you don't
have to do any of this stuff, but I've
scooted up twice now.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
Pom.xml
and uh M7.
There we are. Fantastic. Reload. So,
here's our application.
And we know we're going to build a
controller that'll act as a the thing
that we can ask questions to, right? So
system controller and uh just have an
endpoint here with a user context and
then the inquiry endpoint, right?
>> Uh inquire. So I'll say string inquire
and uh we're going to use to do our
work. We're going to talk to a chat
model and that chat model by the way is
going to be connected. We're going to
connect to it via open AI. Uh and we
have a key there. Now friends, I've
already I've already exported an
environment variable here like so.
Right? So that's already done in the my
shell and spring boot will normalize
that into the property that you just saw
there a second ago. These two are the
same, but you need to specify that
yourself when you connect. Okay, we're
also going to connect to a data source,
not that one. Spring data source uh URI
JDBC colon postgresql,
right? Local host
my database and then we'll create the
username my user and then the password
is secret. Okay, go back to here and
we're going to use the chat client that
was just uh we can it's got a there's a
chat model and then you can use a chat
client. You can create as many of these
chat clients as you want that will talk
to the chat model behind the scenes. I'm
going to inject the chat client builder
and build a new one. And here I'm going
to put my defaults and then I'll use
that model here to answer questions from
the user to this endpoint. Right? So
call.content
etc. And then the prompt is a user
prompt coming from uh the user and
that'll be a request parameter. Right.
Request param string uh question.
So confusing. Ignore this user path
variable for now. Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Let's just try this. So we're going to
start that up.
>> Okay. So a user can hit that endpoint
that inquire endpoint asking a question
as that as that as that variable that
param variable
>> um that request param that then goes to
the chat line
>> which talks to the model.
>> Some stuff talks to the model which is
open AI in this case. does some stuff,
provides an answer, passes it back to
you here.
>> Right. Says, "Nice to see you. Nice to
meet you, Josh. How can I assist you
today?" Great.
>> So, it's We made it wiggle, right?
There's There's a dial tone there.
>> By the dog. By the dog.
>> Yeah. Right. Well, what's my name?
>> I don't have access to Okay. So, it does
It's already forgotten me. Y,
>> right? Yeah.
>> Quite like the first time we met you.
[laughter]
>> I said hi and you're like, "Ah." And
then moved on and we didn't talk for a
year.
>> I can't believe you're lying, John.
[laughter]
>> So, so uh anyway, it doesn't know. So we
need to help it use chatb
APIs.
>> So we need to continue that context. We
send that context back to it every time.
>> Yeah. And the way you do that is by
creating a um uh uh configuring an
advisor. Okay. So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to have a per user uh map,
you know, and I'm going to pass this
chat memory advisor.
Okay. Mhm.
>> So up. There we go. There we go. And
I'll go down here and then the advisor
the the map will say compute if absent
user,
right? And I'm just going to create a
new one if it doesn't exist and I'll
store it in memory. Now there's other
implementations of this chat memory
interface that you can use uh that will
write to different uh abstractions,
right? you can do like neo forj and JDBC
and I think there's one reddus coming
along I don't know but it's all sort of
JDBC of course you know all that stuff
so okay this is an advisor this is like
a filter right uh it's a pre-processor
on the requests intended for the model
and basically as we have a conversation
with the model this will get um stored
per user in that map and then it's a
transcript in effect of everything we
said and that'll be retransmitted to the
on every subsequent request so that the
model remembers oh we talked about abs
and c uh remember it right so here we go
so now we go back and we say uh my name
is Josh
>> great what's my name
>> your name is Josh fine how do you do
right so it's now got memory uh but
let's ask but this is actually kind of a
problem right like which is a like um
what's 2 + two right
yeah okay great but it's not supposed to
be helping people with their homework.
It's supposed to be a model to help
people adopt a dog. Clearly, we've got
we've kind of wandered off in the deep
end here.
>> And this is interesting because you see
a ton of companies. What was the what
was the the there was a couple of big
ones? I think one was was iter or
someone where Yeah, it they were
basically getting it to to like write a
bunch of like malicious code and and
things like that from from the sites
which is kind
>> Amazon for a moment. I think their their
app they have an assistant there. Yeah.
>> And you can actually like
>> somebody prompted prompt poisoned it.
>> Yeah. and got it to like generate code
for them instead of helping them
>> with it was Amazon then like yeah anyway
that's not what we want. So we don't
want this thing getting too off too far
off in the weeds. We have a mission. We
want people to adopt dogs
>> unless you wanted to know how many two
dogs plus another two dogs could be
>> right. So what we want to do is uh is to
um give it a system prompt. The system
prompt is the overall tone and tenor. So
if our system
>> okay here we are and uh cat
desktop talk system. I happen to have a
system pro prompt. Okay, I'll paste that
there. Ah, you know what I just did?
That felt wrong.
>> It's the wrong tool. It's the wrong one.
>> Yeah,
>> there. That's better.
>> Do you know? Do you know
>> when you switched from cat to Doug
there? I was about to make that joke and
I thought, "Oh, no." The only reason I
know that joke is because you said it
last time I saw it a couple of months
ago.
>> I love [laughter] it. So, okay, that's
better. Right. So we're going to say you
are an AI powered assistant to help
people adopt a dog from the adoption
agency called Pooch Palace with
locations in Antworp, Seoul, Tokyo,
Singapore, Paris, Mumbai, Mumbai, New
Delhi, Barcelona, San Francisco, and
London. That's where we are
>> in in Devakuk. And uh information about
the dogs available will be presented
below. There's no information. Return a
polite response suggesting we don't have
any dogs available.
>> I bet if you I bet if you put two plus
two in that prompt, it will still be
your foot.
>> Sure, but we don't want it to.
>> No.
>> Um Okay, so that's a system problem.
that's going to dictate the manner in
which it responds to us, right? It'll
it'll try and frame all responses in
terms of that mission, that overarching
mission. Let's see what it says.
Actually,
>> yeah, it helps, but it gets us back on
track. It's like
>> it's always trying to help, right?
That's the thing with AI. It's like it
has all that background information. It
has a specific bit of context. That
doesn't mean it's going to forget all
the other information. It still knows
how to answer your question. wonderful
snippets from all our speakers, all our
past speakers there, Baroo, Lauran,
Alex, and Josh. And I personally, I'm
looking forward to meeting them all
again uh in New York in in on the 18th
and 19th of November. So, if you can
join us, please do. Uh it's uh it's $90
if you use the code Simon M50 during
checkout. AIDEV.iodevcon io/devcon
to read more about the conference and
also get your tickets there. Hope to see
you there. Uh if you're not in New York,
of course, we're also streaming the main
uh the main stage, so you can uh
register for the virtual only. And also
all sessions will be recorded, so you're
absolutely fine. Uh if you can't make it
there or you're, you know, far away and
want to replay all those sessions,
they'll be on the AI native dev uh site
in not too long. Thanks all for
listening. Thanks for tuning in and see
you next time.